Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're making a phone call.
That's right, we are making a special type
of phone call, we're making a collect call.
So we will explain what this means.
Let's listen to the dialed.
Let's see if you can
more or less guess
what a collect call means
and we'll be right back.
This is the operator, how may I help you?
Yes, I would like to make a collect call.
Okay sir, please dial the number.
Now please state your name.
Tommy.
Please wait a moment.
Hello, you have a collect call from Tommy,
would you like to accept the charges?
Yes, of course.
Dad?
Yeah Tommy, what happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah Dad, everything is okay, I'm calling
you because I want to know if it's okay for
me to go to my friend's
house today after school.
Yeah sure, no problem.
You scared me to death,
I've told you to make
a collect call in case
of an emergency only.
Why didn't you call me
from your mobile phone?
I read a credit and I also didn't have
25 cents for the pay phone, sorry Dad.
Alright, so we're back, we've got a
number of words and phrases to look at.
Let's check out our words
in language takeaway first.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so as we
mentioned, we are making
a collect call, so what
exactly is a collect call?
Alright, well a collect
call is a phone call
you make when you
don't have any money and
the phone company charges the
person who answers the phone.
Okay.
So if I call my mom with a
collect call, my mom pays.
Not you, not me.
And you can do this pretty
much from any phone, right?
That's right, you can
do this from any phone,
normally people use
pay phones to do this.
But there is one condition that
is important with the collect call.
The person who answers the phone, they
have to say that it's okay that they pay.
Okay, you can't just use this with anybody.
Okay, very good.
So actually when the
guy was making this
collect call, the operator
asked him to dial the number.
Okay, so this is an important verb that
we have with making a telephone call.
You don't, you make a
call, but with the number,
the phone number, you
actually have to dial it.
And that comes from those old phones where
you don't push the numbers, you pull them.
Yeah, you had to spin the little wheel.
Yeah, there's circles and you pull the
numbers and spin the wheel around.
But the verb now is to dial a number.
To dial a number, that's right.
Okay, so you dial
your number and well,
actually, as we said,
you're making this collect
call because maybe you
don't have any money.
In this case, sometimes in your mobile
phone, you have what we call credit.
This is an important word.
This is a noun.
You have it or you don't have it.
On my phone, for example,
I have a lot of credit.
But maybe if I don't have any credit, I run
out of credit, I don't have any money left.
I can't make a phone call.
That's right.
So this is what it means when
you have credit in your phone.
It means that you have some
money with the telephone company.
So when you make a call,
they discount it from there.
But if you don't have any more
credit, you can't make any phone calls.
Exactly.
So basically, credit represents money.
That's right.
Okay.
And as you said, a collect call, you
usually make it from a pay phone.
So what is a pay phone?
Okay.
Well, we have phones
at people's houses and
some regular phones and we have
cell phones, which you can carry around.
Well, pay phones are
public phones that you
have to use money in
order to make a call on.
Okay.
Usually you will see these at airports, for
example, airports, train stations, any big
public place for people needs to use phones
of their less common now in some places.
But basically, you have
to put the coins, the
money coins into the phone
to get the phone to work.
Right.
If you don't have any
money, you can't make a call.
Yeah.
That's right.
Okay.
So for keywords there, why don't we take
a break and listen to the dialogue again.
This is the operator.
How may I help you?
Yes.
I would like to make a collect call.
Okay, sir.
Please style the number.
Now please state your name.
Tommy.
Please wait a moment.
Hello, you have a collect call from Tommy.
Would you like to accept the charges?
Yes.
Of course.
Dad.
Yeah, Tommy.
What happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Dad.
Everything is okay.
I'm calling you because
I want to know if it's
okay for me to go to my
friend's house today after school.
Yeah.
Sure.
No problem.
You scared me to death.
I told you to make a collect
call in case of an emergency only.
Why didn't you call me
from your mobile phone?
I read a credit and I also didn't
have 25 cents for the pay phone.
Sorry, Dad.
All right, now we're going
to talk a little bit more about
the phrases we found in this
dialogue on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So this first phrase
is a phrase that you
might encounter in
many different situations.
But today's situation
is making a collect call.
So we heard this phrase,
please state your name.
That's right.
So you have a verb here to
state your name, state your age.
And that basically means to tell us,
tell me or tell us what is your name.
That's right.
So if I say, hey, you,
state your name,
that means I have to say
my name, Marco, for example.
So you can use it for name, for
age, yes, state your birthday, please.
So this is often what we have to do when
we're on the phone with a service company.
So the bank will ask us, what is your, you
know, state your birthday, please, or state
your last name or state
your phone number, they
want to confirm our,
our personal information.
Okay.
And well, as we heard it, so once
you do all this, you make a collect call.
The person on the other side
has to accept, and this is when
the operator said, would
you like to accept the charges?
In this case, to accept the
charges means to offer to pay.
Okay.
So if you accept the
charges, that means that
the phone company will
ask you for money, right?
When your bill comes.
That's right.
So you accept to be charged
with money, or you accept
the charges that come
with this telephone call.
That's right.
All right.
And now the dad finally says, are you
okay, you know, is everything all right?
And apparently it was a very trivial thing.
He just called to make sure that
he can go to his friend's house.
And the dad said, you scared me to death.
Okay.
Parents often use this phrase in English.
This means you had me very worried.
I was so worried.
So you scared me to death.
That doesn't mean that the father died.
Right.
I mean, he was very, very, very scared.
Exactly.
So it's a phrase a
little bit, obviously, with
exaggeration, but very common
to hear, you scared me to death.
You scared me a lot.
Yes.
And why did he scare
him to death because he
told his son to make a collect
call in case of an emergency only?
Okay.
So this phrase in case of an
emergency is a fixed phrase.
You can see this on the metro.
You can see this on the bus, but
also you can hear this in conversation.
And so in case of an
emergency means only
when there is an
emergency situation, a fire,
an accident, something like that.
That's right.
It may be on a train you
have seen or on an airplane.
You have a big red button or a lever
that says pull in case of emergency.
That means don't pull it now, but
pull it if there's a serious problem.
That's right.
So the father says, you know what?
I told you only make a collect
call in case of an emergency.
That means if there's an accident, if the
boys in the hospital, if there is something
serious happening, then it's okay
to charge to make this collect call.
But other times like, you know, you forgot
your wallet, that's not an emergency.
Yeah.
All right.
Very good.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue
one last time and we'll be right back.
This is the operator, how may I help you?
Yes, I would like to make a collect call.
Okay, sir.
Please dial the number.
Now, please state your name.
Hello, you have a collect call from Tommy.
Would you like to accept the charges?
Yes, of course.
Dad.
Yeah, Tommy, what happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah, Dad.
Everything is okay.
I'm calling you because I
want to know if it's okay
for me to go to my friends
house today after school.
Yeah, sure.
No problem.
You scared me to death.
I've told you to make a collect
call in case of an emergency only.
Why didn't you call me
from your mobile phone?
I read a credit and I also didn't
have 25 cents for the pay phone.
Sorry, dad.
So making a collect call,
very common thing as well.
This is the scenario you will
find in the United States, for
example, if you go to a pay
phone, you don't have any money.
You want to call your
friend, the tour guide,
the airport, anything,
you can make a collect call.
That's right.
And this is something that is, like I said,
becoming less common with cell phones.
But generally speaking,
if you don't have
any money and you have an emergency situation
or you need to call someone, it's very
important, then you
can make a collect call.
You dial 0 for the operator
and you say, I want to make a
collect call and they will ask
you these important questions.
And then what the other
person here is is, you
know, Catherine would
like to make a collect call.
Right.
Exactly.
Will you accept the
charges and, you know,
if you're my mother,
you'll say, yes, that's right.
Now, as you said, pay
phones, they used to be all
over the place and you
would have to put in a quarter.
This is why the kids said that he didn't
have any money for the pay phone.
But now, you don't really see too many
pay phones, everyone's got mobile phones.
That's right.
And pay phones are
less and less common,
although a lot of people
like to use pay phones
just because they're
private, not tracked.
Yeah.
But what I've found is
that the airports now,
you can't use a pay phone
with quarters or money.
Now you got to use a credit
card to use a pay phone.
That's right.
It's become so
expensive that you have to
swipe your credit card
to use the pay phone.
Pay phones.
Yeah.
It's a changing world marker.
Now, can we make
international collect calls?
I don't think so.
No.
I don't think it's just America.
Okay.
Well, this is a very interesting topic.
Obviously, we will
see if in your country,
you can make collect
calls or how do you make
a call to someone if you
don't have any money?
That's a good question.
So let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]